A Guide to the Papers of The Center for Nursing Historical Inquiry 1934-2001
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- CNHI: The JoAnne Peach Papers, 8 boxes, 3.5 linear feet
  - Series 4: Publications, Media Clippings, Presentations
    - Publications 1962-1985 (Box-folder 008-000)
      Part Two Examination of the Heart: Inspection and Palpation of Venous and Arterial Pulses, 1967, brochure, 41 pgs.,
      Part Three Examination of the Heart Inspection and Palpation of the Anterior Chest, 24 pgs.,
      Part Four Examination of the Heart Examination of the Heart Auscultation, 71 pgs.,
      Part Five Examination of the Heart:The Electrocardiogram, 81 pgs.
      Essentials of the Neurological Examination by SmithKline Corporation, 1962, 56 pgs
      Essentials of the Neurological Examination by SmithKline Corporation, revised 1979
      Introduction to Arrhythmia Recognition, by California Health Association, 1968 brochure
      Essentials of the Neurological Examination, by Smith, Kline & French, 1968, brochure, 49 pgs.
      Essentials of the Gynecologic History and Examination, by SK&F Services, 1965, booklet, 24 pgs.
      Disorders of the Heart Beat, by American Heart Association, brochure, 1972
      Three Dimensional Views of the Ocular Fundus with an Audio Presentation, by Walter M. Kirkendall, M.D., 1973, cassette, 15 min. and (8) slides
      The Clinical Significance of the Sounds of Korotkoff, (1) cassette, by Abe Ravin, M. D. with manual
      Auscultatory Analysis and Differentiation of Cardiac Valvular Murmurs, (1) cassette, with manual by Abe Ravin, M.D.
      Physical Assessment: The Head and Neck, User's Guide, Medcom, Inc., 1985, booklet, 10 pgs.
      Physical Assessment: The Lungs, User's Guide, Medcom, Inc., 1985, booklet, 10 pgs
      Physical Assessment: The Heart,User's Guide, Medcom, Inc., 1985, booklet, 10 pgs
      Physical Assessment: The Abdomen, User's Guide, Medcom, Inc., 1985, booklet, 10 pgs.
      Physical Assessment: The Neurologic Exam, User's Guide, Medcom, Inc., 1985, booklet, 10 pgs.
      Physical Assessment: The Musculoskeletal System, User's Guide, Medcom, Inc., 1985, booklet
      Physical Assessment: The Female Reproductive System, User's Guide, Medcom, Inc., 1985, booklet, 10 pgs
      Physical Assessment: The Integumentary System, User's Guide, Medcom, Inc., 1985, booklet, 10 pgs.
      Variations and Minor Departures in Infants, By Mead Johnson, 1978, booklet, 48 pgs.
      Patient Assessment: Neurological Examination Part I, workbook, 24 pgs., American Journal of Nursing
      Patient Assessment: Neurological Examination Part II, workbook, 24 pgs., American Journal of Nursing
      Patient Assessment: Neurological Examination Part III, workbook, 24 pgs., American Journal of Nursing
      Patient Assessment: Examination of the Abdomen, 1974, American Journal of Nursing,
      Patient Assessment: Examination of the Heart and Great Vessels Part I, 1976, American Journal of Nursing, (24) pgs
      Patient Assessment: Examination of the Heart and Great Vessels Part II, Feb. 1977, American Journal of Nursing, (22) pgs.
      Patient Assessment: Examination of the Chest and Lungs, 1976, American Journal of Nursing
      Patient Assessment: Examination of the Ear, 1978, American Journal of Nursing
      Patient Assessment: Examination of the Eye Part I American Journal of Nursing, (24) pgs
      Patient Assessment: Examination of the Eye Part II American Journal of Nursing, (22) pgs
      Patient Assessment :Taking a Patient's History 1974 American Journal of Nursing
      Patient Assessment Examination of the Head and Neck, American Journal of Nursing
      Patient Assessment Examination of the Female Pelvis Part I, 1978 26 pgs. American Journal of Nursing
      Patient Assessment Examination of the Female Pelvis Part II, 1978, 28 pgs., American Journal of Nursing
      Patient Assessment: Examination of the Male Genitalia, American Journal of Nursing Aprtil 1979 (24) pgs
      Blood-Gas and Acid Base Concepts in Respiratory Care, 1976 (30) pgs. 1979 P-37 American Journal of Nursing
      Patient Assessment: Pulses 1979 American Journal Nursing Company (26) pgs.
      G. I. Series,
      Physical Examination of the Abdomen Part 1 Inspection, A. H. Robbins, 1969.
      Physical Examination of the Abdomen Part 2, Palpitation, A. H. Robbins, 1969.
      Physical Examination of the Abdomen Part 3. Percussion, A. H. Robbins, 1969.
      Physical Examination of the Abdomen Part 4. Auscultation, A. H. Robbins, 1969.
      Physical Examination of the Abdomen Part 5. Abdominal pain, A. H. Robbins, 1969.
      Physical Examination of the Abdomen Part 6. Differential Diagnosis of Abdominal Disorders, A. H. Robbins, 1972.
      The Infant Child Part 1 Abdominal Examination, A. H. Robbins, 1974
      Anxiety Recognition and Intervention, programmed instruction, workbook, 1965 P-1
      Understanding Defense Mechanisms, programmed instruction, 1972. P-12
- CNHI: Catalog of the Jeanette Chamberlain SERPN Archives, 12 boxes, 5.0 linear feet
  The materials in this collection consist of the Jeanette Chamberlain SERPN (Society for Education and Research in Psychiatric-Mental Health Nursing) archives. SERPN was officially organized on October 13, 1986. The collection contains information on the background of psychiatric-mental health nursing education and research, specifics about the formation and history of the Society for Education and Research in Psychiatric nursing during the period 1986 to 1999 when the autonomous organization became a member in an alliance of psychatric organizations. Dr. Chamberlain was Chief of the Psychiatric Education Training Branch of NIMH and was a strong supporter of SERPN within the Institute during its formative years.
  The collection has been arranged into 5 record groups: Record Group 1: Government Aid to P-MH Nursing Programs (1 Box), Record Group 2: Directors of Programs in Psychiatric-Mental Health Nursing (2 boxes), Record Group 3: Society for Education and Research in Psychiatric-Mental Health Nursing Education (7 boxes), Record Group 4: American Nurses Association (1 box), Record Group 5: Jeanette Champerlain Papers (1 box).
  - Record Group 1: Government Aid to P-MH Nursing Programs
    - HEW 1978-79 (Box-folder 001-001)
    - HHS 1980-93 (Box-folder 001-002)
    - NIMH 1985 Confernce Master List Participants 1985 (Box-folder 001-003)
    - NIMH Task Force on Nursing September 1987 (Box-folder 001-004)
    - NIMH 1986 Orrespondence (Box-folder 001-005)
    - NIMH: National Advisory Mental Health Council 1998 (Box-folder 001-006)
    - NIMH: NIH Research Priority Setting Process 1998 (Box-folder 001-007)
    - NMHLF 1998-89 (Box-folder 001-008)
    - NMHLF 1990 (Box-folder 001-009)
    - NMHLF 1991 (Box-folder 001-010)
    - NMHLF 1992 (Box-folder 001-011)
    - NMHLF Regional Workshops 1987 (Box-folder 001-011)
  - Record Group 2: Directors of Programs in Psychiatric-Mental Health Nursing 1980-85
    - Report of a Conference, National Mental Health Act June 1971 (Box-folder 001-001)
    - Directors of Psychiatric-Mental Health Nursing Program 1979-80 (Box-folder 001-002)
    - Directors of Graduate Programs in Psychiatric-Mental Health Nursing 1980-82 (Box-folder 001-003)
    - Council of Directors of Graduate Programs in Psychiatric-Mental Health Nursing- by laws 1980 (Box-folder 001-004)
    - CDGP Curriculum Task Force 1982 (Box-folder 001-005)
    - CDGP 1981 (Box-folder 001-006)
    - CDGP 1982 (Box-folder 001-007)
    - CDGP 1983 (Box-folder 001-008)
    - CDGP 1984 (Box-folder 001-009)
    - CDGP: Conference Evaluation Forms 1984 (Box-folder 001-010)
    - CDGP: Seattle Conference 1985 (Box-folder 001-011)
    - CDGP: Chevy Chase Conference 1985 (Box-folder 002-001)
    - CDGP: Small Group Reports 1985 (Box-folder 002-002)
    - CDGP: Chevy Chase Conference 1986 (Box-folder 002-003)
    - CDGP: Graduate Programs (Box-folder 002-004)
    - CDGP: Draft Report Regional Conferences in Psychiatric-Mental Health Nursing (Box-folder 002-005)
    - CDGP:Regional Conferences 1987 (Box-folder 002-006)
  - Record Group 3: Society for Education and Research in Psychiatric-Mental Health Nursing (SERPN) 1980-85
    - SERPN: Historical Notes 1986-98 (Box-folder 001-001)
    - SERPN: Bylaws (Box-folder 001-002)
    - SERPN: Blueprint for the Future of Mental Health Services 1980 (Box-folder 001-003)
    - SERPN: Broadsides 1986 (Box-folder 001-004)
    - SERPN: Boards, Committees 1988- (Box-folder 001-005)
    - SERPN: President's Letters 1988 (Box-folder 001-006)
    - SERPN: Logo & Pin 1989 (Box-folder 001-007)
    - SERPN: Strategic Plans 1990-1997 (Box-folder 001-008)
    - SERPN: Archives of Psychiatric Nursing: Correspondence 1991-1998 (Box-folder 001-009)
    - SERPN: Management Services Agreement 1990, 1992 (Box-folder 001-010)
    - SERPN: Financial Records Books 1990-92 (Box-folder 001-011)
    - SERPN: Directory of Nurse Researchers, Administrators, and Educators 1991 (Box-folder 001-012)
    - SERPN: Conference Expenses 1992-1994 (Box-folder 001-013)
    - SERPN: Panic Disorder Education Program 1993-94 (Box-folder 001-014)
    - SERPN: Newsletter 1990 (Box-folder 001-015)
    - SERPN: Membership Lists 1991 (Box-folder 001-016)
    - SERPN: Proposed Budget Form 1994 (Box-folder 001-017)
    - SERPN: Position Statement 1994 (Box-folder 001-018)
    - SERPN: First Research Project 1995 (Box-folder 001-019)
    - SERPN: Taylor: Omnia Opera Addresses 1985-98 (Box-folder 001-020)
    - SERPN: Income Tax Summary 1992-97 (Box-folder 002-001)
    - SERPN: Treasurer's Reports 1994-95 (Box-folder 002-002)
    - SERPN: Archives Expenses 1993-96 (Box-folder 002-003)
    - SERPN: Income Reports 1996 (Box-folder 002-004)
    - SERPN: Saving Account 1996 (Box-folder 002-005)
    - SERPN: Printing Expenses 1996 (Box-folder 002-006)
    - SERPN: Postal Expenses 1996 (Box-folder 002-007)
    - SERPN: Finance Committee 1997 (Box-folder 002-008)
    - SERPN: Membership List 1998 (Box-folder 002-009)
    - SERPN: Financial Reports 1996 (Box-folder 002-010)
    - SERPN: Financial Reports 1997 (Box-folder 002-011)
    - SERPN: Financial Reports 1998 (Box-folder 002-012)
    - SERPN: Financial Reports 1999 (Box-folder 002-013)
    - SERPN: Ethical Issues in Managed Health Care October 16, 1996 (Box-folder 002-014)
    - SERPN: Quality Indicators for Primary Mental Health 1997 (Box-folder 002-015)
    - SERPN: Practice Guideline Coalition 1197 (Box-folder 002-016)
    - SERPN: Team Residency at Ballagio Center 1997 (Box-folder 002-017)
    - SERPN: Telehealth Working Group 1997-98 (Box-folder 002-018)
    - SERPN: Heatlh Care Financing Administration [HCFA] 1997 (Box-folder 002-019)
    - SERPN: Annual Conference 1987 (Box-folder 003-001)
    - SERPN: Annual Conference 1988 (Box-folder 003-002)
    - SERPN: Annual Conference 1989 (Box-folder 003-003)
    - SERPN: Annual Conference 1990 (Box-folder 003-004)
    - SERPN: State of the Art Conference 1990 (Box-folder 003-005)
    - SERPN: Annual Conference 1991 (Box-folder 003-006)
    - SERPN: Program, 1992 Conference 1992 (Box-folder 003-007)
    - SERPN: Keynote Speaker, 1992 Conference 1992 (Box-folder 003-008)
    - SERPN: Registration List for 1992 Conference 1992 (Box-folder 003-009)
    - SERPN: Call for Abstracts, 1992 Conference 1992 (Box-folder 003-010)
    - SERPN: Pre-Conference Workshop 1992 (Box-folder 003-011)
    - SERPN: Pre-Conference Board Meeting November 4, 1992 (Box-folder 003-012)
    - SERPN: Annual Conference 1992 (Box-folder 003-013)
    - SERPN: Moderators, 1992 Conference 1992 (Box-folder 003-014)
    - SERPN: Annual Business Meeting November 6, 1992 (Box-folder 003-015)
    - SERPN: Post Conference Board Meeting November 7, 1992 (Box-folder 003-016)
    - SERPN: Committee Reports, 1992-93 1992-93 (Box-folder 003-017)
    - SERPN: Education Workshops March 28, 1993 (Box-folder 003-018)
    - SERPN: Mid-Year Board Meeting March 29, 1993 (Box-folder 003-019)
    - SERPN: Program 1993 Conference 1993 (Box-folder 003-020)
    - SERPN: Participant Roster, 1993 Conference 1993 (Box-folder 003-021)
    - SERPN: Pre-Conference Board Meeting November 3, 1993 (Box-folder 003-022)
    - SERPN: Pre-Conference Education Institute November 3, 1993 (Box-folder 003-023)
    - SERPN: Abstracts, 1993 Conference 1993 (Box-folder 003-024)
    - SERPN: Annual Conference 1993 (Box-folder 003-025)
    - SERPN: Annual Business Meeting November 5, 1993 (Box-folder 003-026)
    - SERPN: Post-Conference Agenda November 6, 1993 (Box-folder 003-027)
    - SERPN: Two Non-SERPEN Conferences 1993 (Box-folder 003-028)
    - SERPN: Advanced Practice Psychiatric Project March 24-26, 1994 (Box-folder 004-001)
    - SERPN: Program, 1994 Conference 1994 (Box-folder 004-002)
    - SERPN: Call for Abstracts, 1994 Conference 1994 (Box-folder 004-003)
    - SERPN: Research Workshop 1994 (Box-folder 004-004)
    - SERPN: Guest Speakers & Moderators, 1994 Conference 1994 (Box-folder 004-005)
    - SERPN: Participant Roster, 1994 Conference 1994 (Box-folder 004-006)
    - SERPN: Annual Conference 1994 (Box-folder 004-007)
    - SERPN: Post Conference Board Meeting November 4, 1994 (Box-folder 004-008)
    - SERPN: Annual Business Meeting November 4, 1994 (Box-folder 004-009)
    - SERPN: Committee Reports 1994 (Box-folder 004-010)
    - SERPN: Post-Conference Research Institute November 5, 1994 (Box-folder 004-011)
    - SERPN: Evaluation of 1994 Conference 1994 (Box-folder 004-012)
    - SERPN: Perconference Workshop on Managed Care November 1, 1995 (Box-folder 004-013)
    - SERPN: Annual Conference 1995 (Box-folder 004-014)
    - SERPN: Program for 1996 Conference 1996 (Box-folder 004-015)
    - SERPN: Annual Conference 1996 (Box-folder 004-016)
    - SERPN: Keynote address for 1996 conference 1996 (Box-folder 004-017)
    - SERPN: Washington November 6-8, 1996 (Box-folder 005-001)
    - SERPN: Pre-Conference Board Meeting November 4, 1998 (Box-folder 005-002)
    - SERPN: Chicago November 5-8, 1998 (Box-folder 005-003)
    - SERPN: Annual Conference 1998 (Box-folder 005-004)
    - SERPN: Address Book November 20, 1998 (Box-folder 005-005)
    - SERPN: Minutes 1987-89 (Box-folder 006-001)
    - SERPN: Minutes 1987-89 (Box-folder 006-002)
    - SERPN: Minutes 1990 (Box-folder 006-003)
    - SERPN: Minutes 1991 (Box-folder 006-004)
    - SERPN: Minutes 1992 (Box-folder 006-005)
    - SERPN: Minutes 1993 (Box-folder 006-006)
    - SERPN: Minutes 1994 (Box-folder 006-007)
    - SERPN: Minutes 1995 (Box-folder 006-008)
    - SERPN: Minutes 1996 (Box-folder 006-009)
    - SERPN: Minutes 1997 (Box-folder 006-010)
    - SERPN: Minutes 1998 (Box-folder 006-011)
    - SERPN: Minutes April-June 1998 (Box-folder 007-001)
    - SERPN: Minutes July-September 1998 (Box-folder 007-002)
    - SERPN: Minutes October-December 1998 (Box-folder 007-003)
    - SERPN: Minutes 1999 (Box-folder 007-004)
    - SERPN: COPNO History 1987 (Box-folder 007-005)
    - SERPN: COPNO Minutes 1989-91 (Box-folder 007-006)
    - SERPN: COPNO 1996-97 (Box-folder 007-007)
    - SERPN: Out of COPNO comes the Alliance of Psychiatric-Mental Health Nurses January 1998 (Box-folder 007-008)
    - SERPN: Expansion folder - Survey & Responses of Certified Psychatric Nurse Specialists (Box-folder 007-009)
  - Record Group 4: American Nurses Association 1973-97
    - American Nurses Association Resource List 1973 (Box-folder 001-001)
    - American Nurses Association 1976-79 (Box-folder 001-002)
    - Nurses' Coalition for Legislative Action 1985 (Box-folder 001-003)
    - American Nurses Association 1986-97 (Box-folder 001-004)
    - Agenda for Heatlh Care Reform 1991-92 (Box-folder 001-005)
    - Report on Curriculum Survey April 1996 (Box-folder 001-006)
    - Psychotherapy Codes 1997 (Box-folder 001-007)
    - Certification of Psychiatric Nurse Practitioners 1997 (Box-folder 001-008)
    - HIV/AIDS Education for P/MH Nurses 1997 (Box-folder 001-009)
    - American Nurses' Credentialing Center 1997 (Box-folder 001-010)
    - Standards of Clinical Nursing Practice 1997-98 (Box-folder 001-011)
    - American Nurses' Credentialing Center 1998 (Box-folder 001-012)
    - Nursing Journal Articles 1982-83 (Box-folder 001-013)
    - Nursing Journal Articles 1984 (Box-folder 001-014)
    - Nursing Journal Articles 1985 (Box-folder 001-015)
    - Nursing Journal Articles 1985-87 (Box-folder 001-016)
    - Conference: Child and Adolescent Mental Health February 20-21, 1992 (Box-folder 001-017)
  - Record Group 5: Jeanette Goodwin Nehren Chamberlain Papers
    - Biographical Material (Box-folder 001-001)
    - Letters About (Box-folder 001-002)
    - SERPN Contract Proposals 1986-1988 (Box-folder 001-003)
    - Misc. Statistics 1960-80 (Box-folder 001-004)
    - NIMH Support for Clinical Training 1948-80 (Box-folder 001-005)
    - NIMH Materials 1983-88 (Box-folder 001-006)
    - Abstracts of Masters' Theses [n.d.] (Box-folder 001-007)
    - Conference: Nursing in Community of Mental Health Services (Box-folder 001-008)
    - Addresses and Articles: On Nursing Education 1963-88 (Box-folder 001-009)
    - Addresses and Articles: On Child Mental Health 1965-88 (Box-folder 001-010)
    - Addresses and Articles: On Continuing Education 1970-81 (Box-folder 001-011)
    - Addresses and Articles: Goverment Related Materials 1977-87 (Box-folder 001-012)
    - Addresses and Articles: Recruitment of Psychiatric-Mental Health Nurses 1982-88 (Box-folder 001-013)
    - Addresses and Articles: Other Professional Writing 1987 (Box-folder 001-014)
    - (Box-folder 001-015)
- CNHI: The Levato Jacobs Thomas Papers, 2 boxes, .8 linear feet
  Levato Jacobs Thomas is a 1951 graduate of the University of Virginia School of Nursing. For twenty-five years, Ms. Thomas was a nurse with the Glassboro (N.J.) Public School system. The focus of the collection is school health education from the late 1960s to the late 1980s.
  The collection has been arranged into two series: Series 1: School Health Services and Series 2: School Health Education
  - Series 1: School Health Services
    - Levato Thomas Career 1982-1990 (Box-folder 001-001)
      Re: Certificates of Appreciation, correspondence.
    - School Health Services - Nursing Education 1965 (Box-folder 001-002)
      Re: Training manual, graded workbook used by L. Thomas.
    - School Health Services: Nursing Responsibilities 1979-1988 (Box-folder 001-003)
      Re: Nurses' schedule, equipment, procedures, performance objectives & expectations, and School Health Service Guidelines.
    - School Health Services: School Policies, General School of Nursing 1977-1990 (Box-folder 001-004)
      Re: Newsletter, schedules, guidelines of Glassboro Public School.
    - School Health Services: Nursing Records 1988-89 (Box-folder 001-005)
      Re: Free lunch class lists, screening records, "alert" lists.
    - School of Health Services: Special Procedures 1989 (Box-folder 001-006)
      Re: Catheterization & Cystic Fibrosis Guidelines.
    - School Health Services: Referral Information 1985-1990 (Box-folder 001-007)
  - Series 2: School Health Education
    - School Health Education 1981-1990 (Box-folder 002-001)
      Re: Programs taught by school nurse, lyme disease articles.
    - School Health Education 1972-1987 (Box-folder 002-002)
      Re: School Nursing Practicums Supervised by L. Thomas, teacher health education programs.
    - School Health Education 1980s (Box-folder 002-003)
      Re: STD, CPR, contraception, infant feeding brochures.
    - School Health Education (Box-folder 002-004)
      Re: Levato practice teaching records.
    - School Health Education [n.d.] (Box-folder 002-005)
      Re: Poster of Human Body, eye tests, medical exam forms, & child safety posters.
    - School Health Education [n.d.] (Box-folder 002-006)
      Re: Bulletin board displays used in nurses office.
- CNHI: Fay Franklin Thomas-Vaden Papers 1939-1996, 2 boxes, .8 linear feet
  Fay Franklin Thomas-Vaden, RN, a 1937 graduate of the Medical College of Virginia Hospital School of Nursing, was active in nursing throughout her life. Upon her death in 1996, her husband, Joseph Vaden of Keysville, Virginia, donated two boxes of papers from Mrs. Vaden's varied nursing career. The collection includes an autobiographical sketch that details various patient experiences she had while working at Walter Reed Hospital from 1944-1945. General Jefferson Randolph Kean, who worked with Dr. Walter Reed to conquer yellow fever, is one of the patients whom Mrs. Vaden describes. General Kean was a great-great grandson of Thomas Jefferson. A photograph and obituaries from two newspapers provide additional information about the nursing career of Fay Franklin Thomas Vaden.
  The Thomas-Vaden collection includes papers from her years as a student at MCV (1934-1935), notes she used as a surgical and obstetric nursing instructor and supervisor in various hospital institutions (1937- 1944), notes from a summer course she took at the University of Virginia on "Curriculums in Schools of Nursing," (1944) and notes from her course in the Army Nurse Corps during World War II.
  - Series 1: The Thomas-Vaden Papers
    - Autobiography 1996, [n.d.] (Box-folder 001-001)
      Re: Chapter 2, My Education and Profession, letter, photo, and obituary.
    - Lecture Notes/Article Review 1930s-1940s (Box-folder 001-002)
      Re: History of nursing, legislation concerning nursing, & nursing education.
    - Nursing - University of Virginia Hospital 1944-45, [n.d.] (Box-folder 001-003)
      Re: Annual report of surgical department, manual of orientation, & lesson plan for surgical nursing.
    - Medical College of Virginia Nursing Procedures 1934-5?, [n.d.] (Box-folder 001-004)
      Re: Manual of nursing procedures.
    - Surgical Nursing Instruction 1937 (Box-folder 001-005)
      Re: Class outlines, notes, bibliography.
    - Surgery 1929 (Box-folder 001-006)
      Re: Instructors' notes.
    - Graduate Nurses Association of Virginia 1940 (Box-folder 001-007)
      Re: Report of nursing service bureau & a study of minimum curriculum revisions.
    - Red Cross 1941 (Box-folder 001-008)
      Re: Membership card.
    - University of Virginia 1944 (Box-folder 001-009)
      Re: Summer 1944: curriculum in schools of nursing.
    - Fairmount General Hospital 1942-1943 (Box-folder 001-010)
    - Nursing Laws - Virginia 1941 (Box-folder 001-011)
    - Surgical Nursing Instruction 1940s (Box-folder 001-012)
      Re: Teaching notes.
    - Surgical Nursing Instruction 1940s (Box-folder 001-013)
      Re: Exams, lab notes, outline.
    - Student papers (diploma) 1930s, [n.d.] (Box-folder 001-014)
      Re: Graded paper, points in social hygiene, student notes, graded lesson plan for pneumonia, mid-term exams, tests, and worksheets.
    - Surgery & Gynecology 1944 (Box-folder 002-001)
      Re: Instructors' notebooks.
    - Army Nursing 1945 (Box-folder 002-002)
      Re: Class schedules, handwritten notes, fliers on chemical warfare, and military law, immunization register and a booklet, "The Nurses' Guide."
    - Emloyment Offers 1946 (Box-folder 002-003)
    - Obstetrics 1946 (Box-folder 002-004)
      Re: Instructor's Notes: 2 notebooks.
    - Medical College of Virgina SON 1946-49 (Box-folder 002-005)
      Re: Teaching notes, faculty listings.
    - European Study Tour 1949 (Box-folder 002-006)
    - Teaching 1954 (Box-folder 002-007)
      Re: Instructional materials.
    - East Tennessee Baptist Hospital 1957-58 (Box-folder 002-008)
      Re: Obstetrics Nursing exams.
    - Home Nursing 1959 (Box-folder 002-009)
    - Teaching - East Tennesee Baptist Hospital 1957-61 (Box-folder 002-010)
      Re: Teaching materials.
    - Patient Information 1957 (Box-folder 002-011)
      Re: Booklets on colostomies, hospital bills, and clinical norms.
    - Miscellaneous Brochures, paper artifact 195-s (Box-folder 002-012)
      Re: Home protection.